Seeber, Ronald, and Robert S. Smith New York State Workers Compensation Pilot Program for Alternative Dispute Resolution Files /4250
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ronald Seeber and Robert S. Smith New York State Workers Compensation Pilot Program for Alternative Dispute Resolution Files
1991- 2001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seeber, Ronald Leroy
Smith, Robert Stewart
/4250
6.5 cubic feet
6.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8058612
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 13, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Ron Seeber is a Senior Vice Provost at Cornell University and a Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations. He received his B.S. in Industrial Engineering from Iowa State University in 1975. He attended the Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, from which he received his A.M. (1977) and Ph.D. (1981).
Robert S. Smith, the Associate Dean for Academic Affairs in the School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, is also a Professor in the School's Labor Economics Department. After receiving his Ph.D. in Economics at Stanford University in 1971, he taught at the University of Connecticut and worked as an economist in the U.S. Department of Labor before coming to Cornell in 1974. He has authored numerous articles in the field of labor economics and is co-author of Modern Labor Economics: Theory and Public Policy, the leading textbook in its field for 3 decades (and now in its 12th edition).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4218: Ron Seeber Collection of Labor Videos /4297: ILR School Biography Files /4061: Robert Aronson Selected Files 6007: U.S. Department of Labor Office of American Workplace Labor Management Cooperation Collected Publications /4227: ILR School Timothy Schmidle ADR Files /4264 PUBS: ILR School Communications Department Publications /4283: ILR School Extension Division (Buffalo, N.Y.) Files 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 6007: U.S. Department of Labor Office of American Workplace Labor Management Cooperation Collected Publications 6220: U.S. Commission on the Future of Worker-Management Relations (Dunlop Commission) Documents 6346 PUBS: Seyfarth Shaw Labor Publications 6391: William B. Gould IV NLRB Papers
Dispute resolution (Law); Workers' compensation; Seeber, Ronald Leroy; Smith, Robert Stewart; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8058612
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Tim Schmidle, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs; Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim Forms, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Workers' Compensation, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Worker's Compensation Alternative Dispute Resolution, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Transmittal's from Brenda Rigas, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Workers' Compensation Alternative Dispute Resolution Pilot Project, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Workers' Comp. Pilot Program, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Workers' Compensation Misc., 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Workers' Compensation Pilot Program Evaluation (ILR), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 'To Ron Seeber', 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Workers' Comp. Managed Care Pilot Project; Final Report to the Legislature, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Workers' Compensation Alternative Dispute Resolution Project Misc., 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Workers Comp. Memos, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Workers Comp. Memorandums and Vouchers, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Peer Review Committee (Listing, Letters, Correspondence), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Smith, Seeber, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Articles (1994) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- To: Robert Smith, Ron Seeber; From: Tim Schmidle, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Workers Compensation Memos, Drafts, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Robert S. Smith, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 'To: Labor Management Committee', 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Workers Comp. Dissertations presented to Graduate School Faculty Cornell University, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Workers' Compensation Study 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Quarterly Summaries, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Computer - Assisted Surveying Facility Prospectus/ y. DiCiccio, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- RPI/RWJF, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Survey of Injured Workers in NYS -6 Month. Post - Injury, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Survey of Health Care Professionals Regarding Quality of Care Indicators in Workers' Comp: Survey Promises, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Supervisor Survey, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Injured Worker Survey, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Summary of Potential Statistical Models Regarding Quality Lost of Medicare Care, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Draft for "Request for Proposals" Regarding Medical Records Renew, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- ADR Workplan, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- ADR Procedure Log, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Barbara Deinhardt, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Articles and Clipping Re: WCMCP and WCADRP, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Workers' Compensation Collective Bargaining/ Alternative Dispute Resolution Pilot, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- From: Tim Schmidle, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Ron Seeber, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- College Bargaining Agreements, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Request for Proposals: Workers' Compensation Medical Records Review, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Printed Emails and Ron's Hand Written Notes form Meetings, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Reports and Papers Re: WCMCP and WCADRP, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Reports and Papers Re: WCMCP and WCADRP, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Reports and Papers Re: WCMCP and WCADRP, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Workers' comp. Board Committee (Listing, Letters Correspondence), 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Labor-Management Committee (Listing, Letters, Correspondence), 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Data Files (Yasamin's), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Comments and Bios from PRC, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Florida, New Hampshire Managed Care Programs, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Bibliography -, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Consultant List, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 12-93 Laws + 6-94 Laws, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- DOH Regs, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- DOL Regs, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Tim Schmidle/ John Burton, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Data Manual (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Government Affairs Articles, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- CISER, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- The White Paper, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Correspondence w/ Companies Wanting to part-take in NC Study, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Membership Agreement + Software License - CATI/ Berkeley, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Mail Survey - 1/6/95, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Telephone Survey 10/27/94, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Research Questions, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Claims Data Needs, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Ratings Board, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Legislation and Pilot Projects Matrixes, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Minutes and Agendas and Attendees of Mtgs., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Consultants Forms vouchers and Consultants, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Expenses + Computers, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Blank Approval forms and Consultant forms (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Administration/Budgets/Internal Memos, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Financial Analysis Statements (Budgets), 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Research Proposals (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Materials/ Articles, 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- An Evaluation of the New York State Workers' Compensation Pilot Program for Alternative Dispute Resolution, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Quarterly Report; Workers' Comp. Pilot Project, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Quarterly Report; Workers' Compensation Pilot Project, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Sept. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: May 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: May 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: June 1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: June 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: July 1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: July 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: April 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Aug. 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Dec. 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Sept. 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Oct. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Oct. 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Nov. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Nov. 1996 cont. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Dec. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- State of NY - Workers' Compensation Board - Alternative Dispute Resolution Program Final Disposition or Settlement of Claim: Aug. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)